Devon Hirth

Design Technologist, Sole Proprietor of exp. design

devon@expdesign.io

Summary

I have been a designer and front-end web developer for 7 years working in advertising and the startup space. My experience ranges from research with human-centered design to prototyping and implementation using identity design, user experience design, interface design, front-end web development, and data visualization.

Most recently, I co-founded a financial data startup called Quadrant.io. Working at an early stage company gave me the opportunity to innovate and work directly with our audience as well as insight into the perspectives of entrepreneurs and the unique challenges they face.

As a designer and engineer, I have come up against many challenges, both creative and technical, and I derive a great deal of satisfaction overcoming them. Some of the most important skills I've learned through being challenged include listening to people's needs, finding insight to supplement knowledge, addressing technical debt, strategizing for successful outcomes, and collaborating with all stakeholders.

Experience

Design Technologist, Sole Proprietor at exp. design

May 2009 - Present (7 years)

I provide brand strategy and full-stack web development services developing identities, stationary, posters, marketing websites, application interfaces, and data visualizations using my skills in Identity/Branding, User Experience Design, User Interface Design, and User Interface Engineering.

Co-Founder, Chief Design Technologist at Quadrant.io

May 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 8 months)

Quadrant.io is a toolkit that provides macroeconomic data. I am responsible for the branding, interface design, and front-end development of Quadrant.io's web application and marketing sites and I am a core contributor of the creative strategy of the company using my skills in Creative Strategy, Creative Direction, Identity/Branding, User Experience Design, User Interface Design, Data Visualization, Front-end Web Development and User Interface Engineering.

Programming language fluency included Python, Django, Flask, Javascript, JSON, D3, Node, Angular, Backbone, LoDash, jQuery, JS Hint, JSCS, NPM, Grunt, Gulp, PHP, Wordpress, Twig, Composer, WPEngine, CSS, LESS, Hologram, Amazon Web Services, EC2, S3, Cognito, Git, Auth0 Authentication Service, and Algolia Search Service.

Design Technologist at Sideways Inc

September 2012 - March 2014 (1 year 7 months)

Sideways NYC is a digital media agency focused digital design and social media strategy for multimedia, entertainment, hospitality, and nightlife brands. I programmed experiences for marketing websites and web applications using my skills in User Experience Design, Web Design, Front-end Web Development, User Interface Design, User Interface Development, and Animation.

Programming language fluency included PHP, Wordpress, Cake, Symphony, Silex, Twig, Composer, Javascript, jQuery, Bower, NPM, Grunt, CSS, LESS, SASS, Subversion, Git, MongoDB.

Interactive Designer at happyMedium

April 2012 - August 2012 (5 months)

happyMedium is a digital creative agency focused on branding, mobile application development, and web development for local agencies, start-ups, and national brands. I designed, prototyped, and developed interactive experiences for mobile and desktop applications with a team of designers and developers using my skills in Creative Strategy, Identity/Branding, User Experience Design, Front-end Web Development, User Interface Design, and User Interface Engineering.

Programming language fluency included PHP, Wordpress, Javascript, ¡Query, CSS, LESS.

Interactive Designer and Front-End Web Developer at 2e Creative

October 2009 - March 2012 (2 years 6 months)

2e Creative is an agency that develops smart creative for life sciences, healthcare, and scientific publishing industries. I designed and programmed interactive experiences and produced video content and animations as a multimedia designer in the 2e Creative team using my skills in Creative Direction, Identity/Branding, User Experience Design, Front-end Web Development, User Interface Design, User Interface Engineering, Video Production and Animation.

Programming language fluency included PHP, Wordpress, Javascript, jQuery, Flash, Actionscript, CSS, HTML.

Intern at act3 studio

May 2008 - January 2009 (9 months)

Act3 is a strategic and applied storytelling firm applying the principles of storytelling to help organizations solve their most challenging problems. I gained insight and experience to storytelling strategy along with other interns led directly by the Act3 founders as well as designed and programmed interactive experiences using my skills in Identity/Branding, User Experience Design, Front-end Web Development, User Interface Design, and User Interface Engineering.

Volunteer Experience

Web and Interactive Chair at AIGA St. Louis Chapter

January 2011 - September 2012

The AIGA is a national professional association for design. Serving the local St. Louis chapter I coordinated digital communication between the board and a 358 member association by posting information on our website, managing online event systems, developing email campaigns and special event websites, engaging the community through social media, and event volunteering.

Volunteer Designer at Catchafire

September 2012 - Present

I provide pro-bono design and development consulting to organizations with social causes.

Volunteer Designer at Goodnik

June 2014 - Present

I provide pro-bono design and development consulting to organizations with social causes.

Skills & Expertise

Interaction Design

Branding & Identity

Data Visualization

Creative Direction

Web Design

User Experience

Web Development

Creative Strategy

User Interface Design

Animation

Typography

Illustration

Human-centered Design

Data Driven Applications

Web Components

Templating

JavaScript

D3.js

BEM

AngularJS

Python

PHP

Git

WordPress

Django

Auth0

Auth0 Angular

SASS

Stylus

LESS

jQuery

Education

Maryville University of Saint Louis

BFA, Graphic Design, 2006 - 2009

+Acumen

Human-Centered Design for Social Innovation, 2014 - 2014

General Assembly

Data Science, 2013 - 2014

3rd Ward

Woodworking, Metalworking, Physical Computing, and Processing, 2012 - 2012

Devon Hirth

Design Technologist, Sole Proprietor of exp. design

devon@expdesign.io



2 people have recommended Devon

"Devon is both an exceptional designer and front-end developer. He's easy to work with and takes pride in everything he delivers. He's flexible enough to work with either a fixed set of requirements or a rough idea and make it great."

— Dane Vrabac, Founder and CEO, Quadrant.io, managed Devon at Quadrant.io

"Devon embodies the type of individual who is constantly pushing oneself to new heights yet has his feet firmly planted in the realities of life and the business of doing smart creative. His willingness to tackle any challenge with commitment and dedication to excellence functions as a catalyst to propel any initiative that he undertakes to a heightened level. I am confident that one day he will be viewed as a trend leader within the creative industry."

— Joe Toohey, managed Devon at 2e Creative

Contact Devon on LinkedIn